and realize no it's just like the only
thing that comes to mind in that moment
yeah which is probably better than the
ball what is it whatever I was saying
before them so it is our board medium
for together tech Bentley isn't joining
us today we have a bit of stuff on the
agenda to discuss probably and I'm
getting through that and I'm about ten
minutes so today for the first time
instead of streaming to YouTube and
Facebook simultaneously only streaming
to YouTube and then I posted the link on
Facebook so if you see us just follow it
over to you to being a comment there and
follow the links in the descriptions for
if that's permanent which I don't think
it is today for other ones I'm not
saying that those instructions but
that's fine I mean there's no one
watching so how are they possibly if
you're giving instructions on how to get
from YouTube sorry from Facebook to
YouTube they won't see this unless
they're on YouTube no but if it
autoplays then they can follow their
clicks and then which means I'm just
gonna check you talk oh another person
excellent it's not just us yeah well
Akash I'll oh I'm just gonna I wanted to
meet myself not do that
I can also need affiliated anyway
alright just trying to tell them you cuz
there's the dog barking in the
background so check I'm trying to meet
myself because I want to see if this
Auto played on Facebook's
[Music]
I'm fairly sure it won't
that gives people incentives to put
their videos on Facebook which is what
facebook wants yeah no absolutely their
profit over purpose which they want
people to see videos but not on YouTube
so yeah I think before it was before
they have the ability to go live on
Facebook they don't play in your
interview but knowing that be videos and
stuff yet was since we're we're playing
on Facebook is specifically in the
project space it probably makes sense to
do both so I just wanted to experiment
and see that's a good as of this one and
tomorrow will be the same thing for this
week see how it goes on Facebook we're
just not auto-create on I mean there's a
lot of reasons to go pure YouTube
because then it's easier to with the
interaction is through New York like
that so anyway it's probably enough
talking about all that boring tech stuff
that's kinda it is a board meeting
alright the agenda I know if you'd see
Adriel on because I don't think I sent
you Charlie I just sent you first I
rolled Friday messenger um the FAQ for
together tech I can I thought you put
said I I didn't have a chance to take a
look yet it's very short
the only questions I answered what is
together tech whom is together tech how
can I get involved with together tag
what does together tech do currently and
where can we find out playing the better
when I clicked on the after meeting
myself to see if it was played properly
and all that okay let's put this in your
private jet you can copy a piece for
private check show those you are the FAQ
and Adriel to since you probably don't
have a look right now there's also make
sense more for the people he hurt to go
than people or was watching so the only
thing
I mean I threw it together in like an
afternoon it's just so people can kind
of when we do something on together tech
it can be posted in the description to
the FAQ or just as people I don't even
know how like how people get involved in
the other ten drawing the Facebook group
and then just purchase I need brains now
there's not really much to join like I'm
not sure why you would join right now
unless you're just wanting to
participate in the board meetings I
think yeah but it will become more
important as we actually start to do
things and offer reasons for people to
join so there starts a conflict or
something happens that will have more of
like joining process now it's like show
I can participate see how it doesn't
align with you does it align with us
does it work show participate as much as
you as you want so that is basically
what I think you actually says is that
okay you enjoy the Facebook group
participating the events that's it yeah
because our Fridays you know Fridays at
12 p.m. PST behold we means alternating
between the itea cafe for projects and
the board meetings for creating the meta
project together tech Saturdays at 9:00
a.m. PST we have project roundtables
people with projects or looking for one
come to share what they have been doing
or they could use help with these
sessions are all held live on YouTube
and Facebook so as soon as I wrote that
I didn't follow it up with links to
participate on Facebook we also hold
project raising these would requested oh
that's so I did post a link to
participate for sure a part of it is on
YouTube since anyone can watch I don't
post links participate as the whole
point is not to have random people
another reason to go is it then it
catches people's eye and then people can
write it up in that way that made sense
I think one of the alternatives which I
mean it's kind of I think a big change
but might be worth it it's changing from
I think it's a group to a page cuz like
I don't have any of these problems with
the the wiki Lipson one because that's I
think a page and so like I can stream to
it I can you know I can comment as it
and all that stuff
so we may want to explore that at some
point if we're trying to just improve I
don't pay for a group for a reason we
just want people from that group to come
participate and it's II don't I mean we
don't necessarily want you know my
random high school people to see and
we're doing this to come and participate
it's like people who you're either in
game B or doing something very game be
adjacent and wanted right do not think
for users though like the difference
between a page in a group is almost
negligible to the average person but for
some reason and Facebook on the backend
huge difference we should page versus
group I feel like a page is more just a
company and you're like a customer
following a brand versus a group is like
you're part of it just in the name but I
agree I think it's it's a page as a
brand and together tech we're trying to
build a brand no I know but like I don't
even know if page allows you to have
multiple admin's and make announcements
and you don't I mean like I think
algorithms even though maybe when we're
live it's better it's not necessarily
better when everyone else is posting to
also here I mean like we're trying to
turn it more into a group and a page you
get for them was the experience of being
in it right if like us I mean you liking
it and get in following versus a group
that we're all part of and contributing
to even if people aren't actually
contributing right ok good that makes
sense
and yeah I know that there's going to be
reasons for each just it's interesting
to see the two different sides because
it's been way easier to stream to wait
till wiki election you using stream yard
do you have a lot of people like the
parents will like your page on Wikipedia
are debris collection I think there's
like 30 now many people who like it
there wasn't did you advertise it like
how did you get 30 people to like it or
did you just go live and then people
found you sorry no I'm talking about 30
people liking like the page four were
collection
all right my question is how did those
30 people find you did you just a lot
like mostly from before right where it
was like where I would like you know
when I did the Kickstarter for wiki
election and I posted on my personal
page like you know friends and family
and stuff go and join and then I've had
like I think possibly some people from
game B and like occasional people
showing up and finding it and I assume
it's probably from the game B stuff like
what is it that worked for the wiki
election page that you don't think works
for them together tech just stream yards
streaming to it right like they're when
you're setting up the channels in stream
yard it sort of explains like hey by the
way you're streaming to a page you won't
be able to do this this this and this
like you know I get I think it's harder
for it to like where that person has to
like yeah I think that's a like stream
yard or something and then we shouldn't
see there yeah like it's it's just it's
the whole connection between stream yard
and Facebook is easier and better if
you're a group a patient said of a group
yeah oh hey brands and does sound like
for-profit companies but not groups
grassroots no don't happening or it's
just a glitch that's the a thank you I
don't even know where we necessarily
want to use it what we want to add to it
but it's a good place as we hear Carmen
questions to have one place to store
them he turned us like for internal use
right if anyone came in the private chat
is the link to the agenda on the FAQ
talk Wednesday FAQ the bottom one is the
agenda agenda you can see there's weeks
we don't fill it out this week it just
has a date it's like ferry and we just
fill it out as we just add things
sometimes sometimes we take notes but
they're all up all of our board meetings
are available as a hour-long video
so even if we don't take notes it's
still there for what and so that's
basically that's all I had on the agenda
40 other tack I know
here though I think we could possibly
talk about our solution raising or we
did talk about macking maybe that was
kind of a together tech project I didn't
hunted together tech project or anyone
else has anything they'd like to add for
more of like how do we discuss the
matter project or move the meta project
forward whatever anyone else would like
to add to the agenda even if they didn't
know the agenda existed I'm psychic you
know absolutely curious about how do you
see the together tech being not
identical but very connected to the meta
project because it seems that they are
kind of the same thing yeah there are
two ladies it's just if we see a matter
project people in camp you know we're
talking about together attack it's like
it's just the name of the meta project
because together tech isn't necessarily
game B even if it's 90% gave me people
it's the idea that you don't need to
understand game BD KP game be right to
know that we need a better world that
you're trying to create all new in
solutions that are not it's kind of more
of the important part so it was already
had the name together attack and then we
were kind of like we need a name for the
meta project and became the two are an
analogous yeah so it's kind of like our
flavor of you know the like trying to
figure out how we can help projects move
forward as a group the whole thing
it started out talking as the matter
project cuz it's a project of about
projects and as Julie said it sort of
became up we were trying to brand it and
Jubilee have the name together tech and
it fits quite well with what is trying
to do so but yeah they're they're
synonyms all three it's so yellow here
at state another project game B projects
and together tech it's all basically the
same thing yeah and then fortunately
fortunately together tech is also
synonymous with like a technology
cooperative in general that something
that like humanity owns together the
members own together because we don't
have a project and number itself isn't
the meta project
now it's also like how to get to a
technology cooperative we all own part
of it is creating it from the ground up
which is solution raising you to
figuring out a process do that and then
also bringing people's projects together
to great bring them in the world and
creating common solutions so we're kind
of attacking it from all angles at the
same time and together attack is
somewhat the umbrella for that and
somewhat hard to contain conversation
and it's like our version of game P and
how to create it without opening game be
right without being like can't these are
isn't anyone who's involved in it you
like it's you know whether you're
involved in together attack or not right
you don't necessarily know if you're
going to give you so it's like the first
step first step or the fractal fractal
thing that is supposed to hopefully mmm
yeah I think so mmm-hmm that's kind of
our attempt at it as Jubilee said
intentionally not divorcing ourselves
from from game B but like we're a
separate entity that we aren't claiming
to follow every game B principle 100%
it's more about us trying to move it
forward what does it take to actually
start to work on projects together and
figure that stuff out without getting
bogged down in the mire of well is it
you know you know these three things but
not that one game B element so it's not
game B projects forward that are even
like slightly game B but we established
that the baby is not supposed to be mm
put in words so make sense sorry
it's not supposed to be defined and you
know describe this exactly which get
hard when you're trying to make like an
organization around it cuz you kind of
have to define what you're doing and
what you're about so it's like yeah or
attempt it like here's the flavor that
we think it'll take as far as what a
game B ish organization can look like
but we're almost certainly going to make
choices that the gay B community doesn't
fully uh agree with and they're welcomed
you know give feedback and or start
their own coops you know we can work
together and figure out
we different how are we the same helping
we help each other etc it bring together
individuals hopefully with sovereignty
not how to improve their sovereignty and
then how do like projects come together
to work because that's just where we
started people in game B happen to have
projects or not gonna let go and now
become game B is their project it's like
they want game B to somehow shift and
focus on their project or they just
realize that they can go at this point
if game B went away cuz there was some
scandal or some bad media we don't cease
to exist and similarly you go away we in
no way tarnish game B right like it's
it's very obviously a that P so that you
can't talk about it but also can you be
able to talk about things it's people
who put it out like how do we get to a
better world where does their version of
a better world
what is our path there what is all of
the things that are more nebulous and I
think like if because I tend to think in
a lot of things that sort of game a
terms because I mean I still work in
gaming and there's parts of that I like
I think what we're at now is what we
call indie gaming thought leadership so
it's not like actually selling anything
or doing necessarily the main purpose of
the organization but kind of starting to
show like okay the people involved are
thinking about these areas that's likely
to be what that organization is sort of
you know skill that and focused on and
that kind of thing right so for us we're
doing these you know open meetings and
doing this sort of open thought process
on what does it mean you know to have a
game B project or to have that kind of a
project and what are the things that it
emphasizes and you know what it's trust
me two people having these public
conversations so anyone else even if
they would never join together tech or a
co-op conviction or access to that
information and at some point as Julie
mentioned the end goal is for it to be
like an actual you know a community
owned co-op that actually owns tech like
you know yeah if it it owns tech but as
a co-op instead of as a for-profit
entity but that part would be optional
like I'm sort of
personally I'm you know I've got wiki
election I'm also part of together tech
guys I think the to work well together
and like that's an example of I'm not
you know going to merge wiki election
with together tech anytime soon but it
helps kind of answer questions it like
for example Bentley might have at the
same time for reason schooler so we can
go on under one umbrella try to solve
all together and then I'll take my
learnings didn't leave or think is you
know you know everyone here well I'll
take their own and then hopefully we
report back and that's where the
learning happens yes and from technical
point of view for all the projects it
would be because they have other lives
be go and small so for all the projects
if they had api's so they could talk
together mmm and be useful to each other
that would be also something that was
yesterday younger mmm
mapping meeting and especially after we
discussed some with James some more
details about how such a system could
look like and at some point for example
we mentioned that it would be useful to
have a set of values defined somewhere
as like a list of possible values that
people might have and adhere to and feel
connected to and for some reason well I
record what our friend Saddam is doing
and his political project and it has the
set of values ready basically and it's
meant to like drill down the values
problem and define and if that project
had an API so other projects that could
need its Freddie somewhere so exists
already and yeah ApS I'm good right
totally
I yeah and I think that that's where you
help for sort of that's something that
together tech provides a spot for you
know so for example it might provide
something sort of like you know user
management and user registration or that
if you don't want to have you know for
example says already has his I've got
together tech we got reason score we got
I'll have all these different apps if we
didn't want especially people in the
game be space you might be trying out
multiple versions of them if we want it
like share user registration and say
like you you know you create a single
user and then you can use that same user
anywhere in this ecosystem kind of like
you know a Google login or Facebook yeah
we're but it's creating something
separate because those names come with a
lot of baggage you know security and
privacy justifiably yeah the kind of an
alternative through something like an
API starting with possibly a user list
or just shared data of some sort so one
thing James of course has its own little
project interesting and we discussed
something like because there are so many
products but so many projects because
people like different styles of you is
and they expect different thing to
visualize they have different needs and
it's good and I guess that's because we
have so many of the other projects but
one interesting thing is the data in in
the backend might be exactly the same
and maybe that even has to be exactly
the same
I mean data can be true or mmm not and
if we had a set of true data on a
subject then all the projects we have
existing in the space could use the same
data but is not it in a different way or
focus on different aspects of the data
so there is also that it was interesting
because it showed why how we can have
the variety of interfaces and users but
working on the same different set of
facts of data and independent of
interfaces right and is there ready to
be used
I see yeah I mean I think wherever
possible we should definitely try to do
that right so if we have three or four
projects all building up the same data
set if one falls away
we don't lose that data that's still
aerial they can all fall away and a new
one can pop up and it would have this
library of data that it could have
access to I think something that
together attack like all of the little
like we need to figure out have fun
together tech right and fund the
individual projects we're actually out
of place so we can actually accept
funding because we haven't worked that
out right right but to develop a commons
even if only in idea that that is the
comments right so whether we collections
working on their project individually or
not what are they what would they
benefit from being in the commons and
what can they give back to the Commons
right right so my example is a lot like
my talk about like having different
recipe apps right once again ones but it
dissipates the energy if there's a
common pool of information the user the
recipes the ingredients they're
attritional information and then you can
have your vegan app and if you don't
even if that app goes away the
informations there the data is still
there the connections are still there
you might be you know join the bigger
recipe group as a vegan subset or join
it like there's a lot more power there
if each individual project is creating
our database then they want on the
database they want to profit off the
database it has to be done with the
Commons in mind a bit like to some
degree again what is Becky like she
could what could they use from the
Commons and what could they give back to
the Commons and that we could figure out
what is the most powerful to create in
the Commons and what we want to get back
maybe with the election give something
back that has nothing to do with wiki
like write the back I don't know
people's postal code information if
they're willing to give it back right
like whenever that happens to be that's
not information that connects to all of
that right if it connects all the
information and as the user hopefully
I'm in control I own data there's a
higher level of information it's
available and then the UI having the UI
be very different based on the diversity
including even having that vegan recipe
site right rather it's the developer
that makes unique or the user that makes
it unique the comments is common right
oh yeah I just realized that talking
about fractally displaying and gathering
data it's not even about in within a
single project that this place a
fracture of information it can also mean
like totally different projects same
thing about factory displacement Stan
I'm like no and using the same users
across all these different apps you know
assuming people opt into all the
different areas could be so insanely
powerful is then if you cease to have a
recipe app and a you know travel app and
this and that you'd be like okay well
this person is eating this they're
shopping here they're doing this they're
going there they can know so much and
you can control it but part of the
reason to have that information stored
because if it's just for you I already
know where I ate something like that but
if as a community we say hey you know
don't take this box if you want open up
these areas and then I have you know an
algorithm or a I stretch a look at this
disconnected stuff and start to learn
and it's being done under a and open
system and beany like being helpful
not-for-profit is the whole thing like
if it was for-profit who gets the money
no one so why would you mm-hmm but that
sort of disconnected information is
where you can get some just crazy
powerful stuff everything that doesn't
exist in the realm of trying to sell you
more and try to hide it for what
you like your answer with that
information we can track over it 19
whatever new pandemic comes like there's
a lot of it we can do they're trying to
do that but you can't like top down
comes with a lot of pushback from the
bottom up where it's the bottom putting
it in place for ourselves is very
different if ten thousands of Vancouver
chose to track our contacts and there
was enough of us that would somehow
extrapolate the rest and would give us
some information and I can have to hope
that the government is going to be in
control of it and do an ethical fashion
that's in every city right like it can
walk around up it just has so much more
power and our data is a big part of that
we're willing to give arm down or more
and are not is more useful I can
literally do everything except the one
thing we're currently doing which it's
powerful but just awesome game beating
collapse faster now they are trying to
make us seals here in Poland this
application to track movement of people
and it's officially it's supposed to be
a very privacy compatible which is my
phone knows only very limited set of
facts about other phones it comes in
contact with and I get the information
that someone I was nearby I was close to
is quarantined and it's it looks on the
surface it looks really like okay it
makes sense it doesn't store
informational but then there is a
central place controlled by the
government basically and it so appears
that they can be called the data that is
not supposed to be colored by anyone and
there is sample CBO you know actually
tracking people aren't doing the China
in here so this whole thing is quite the
test in human sovereignty and technology
and governance in all the way because
there's like this somewhat diabolically
opposed side the left versus the right
and they look very similar in this code
but weird like the right oh my god we
need you behind
it was like we need to close down the
border like it becomes very like you
wanna look like the other side cuz
you're your highest value you need to
live and like what which one does that
look like
what's the point of this that joint now
there's people who like our like our
governments are trying to take out our
rights and you're letting them you're
staying inside your sheep oh you sheeple
get out and protest and take back our
governments the other people who are
like governance or maybe inept but
they're doing the best they can this is
the best we can do right now there is it
like and they're both right like it's
what do we do if though if the
conspiracy theory whichever one is right
right that if the government this is
orchestrated they're doing it to install
5g to whatever whatever whenever get our
fascist apps installed put inject chips
into our arms I don't stop that how do
we see if that's true and if it's the
other side and we think that their
benevolent whatever there's naturally
like that it is just a virus what is our
best course of action then like what is
how do we best help how do we best do
either inside instead of our community
which is true what actually works how
would we actually track ourselves
because it's not the government keeps
calling them on our phone for sure if we
want that if there's a vaccine coming
down the line what would get people who
aren't gonna vaccinate to vaccinate we
need to have those conversations now
because it's not leaving if they get
hands of Bill Gates it's not leaving it
I think at that point you know what
would you get a vaccine but also what
would you need to know or in order to
voluntarily install that app like what
would probably it's not made by a
government that's probably important one
probably it's not made by for-profit
corporations you start to build up okay
if we think that this thing is important
right like okay so if you think that the
whole thing is fake and blah blah blah
what would it take for you to actually
believe it when the government says that
you need to quarantine yourself what
would that look like and vice versa yeah
exactly and if you're right what would
this look like like all of it like
there's the plan plan demmick that's
going around
like i don't care if it's true or not we
need to stop having it like
documentary is our highest level of
media yeah we need a way to understand
what the is going on without
relying on one person's narrative and
put it into a video and then sell it to
us in this britain's diva it's like I
want to know what in this is real what
if this isn't real and then actually be
able to like have a conversation without
instead of just you're wrong you're an
idiot I because I did the research and
put it come to the same conclusion as I
did so you're clearly an idiot okay
summarize the entire political discourse
your idiot because you know you know you
get access to 16 information that I have
and then reach the same conclusions from
the information you probably didn't see
so so you're an idiot yeah one of my
favorite people on Facebook or there are
people in real life and they happened to
be on Facebook posted that a rebuttal
for seven points against planned emic
and if you continue to post it and
pleads on friends me I was like is this
such an alignment with who you are as a
person I don't really like who's why
would I read those seven and come to the
same conclusion as you like no no this
makes sense some of this is like and
then someone rebuttals that well then
you should like it's like it's not just
a way to Cory there isn't even one
narrative about it and there's so many
aspects that it's how to make one sense
because yes there seems to be the virus
yes it's real but when you read about
this specific kind of viruses it becomes
a little stretch like it's I think 7th
of this family that appeared in in the
world and it just happens to be so far
the most lethal which is not to say that
there is no next virus in line just
waiting I already heard some user
there's no strength of this thing and
it's already spreading so yeah there is
that the origins
who knows people accuse oh no it's a
China notice us no it's whatever it came
from animals it came from some
laboratory it escaped
it was released yeah doesn't even matter
if we cannot do anything about it I
don't think it matters if it escapes
from a laboratory we know that military
is working on some stuff like this okay
not much we can do about it
right now I think so the epidemic itself
how problematic is that given that flu
and cancer and whatever else is more
lethal than this one so you have this
problem and then regardless of of all of
this when the pandemic was announced
like everyone in power just jumped with
joy and said okay this is what we are
going to use it they just started using
it for everything and allows the vaccine
in my country sometimes they have
nothing to do with an epidemic or any
just they are shoveling this whole thing
as much as they are able to yeah I think
that is that's definitely happening here
yes so it's crazy and yeah that's just
another angle to look at it then you
have the application and this opens oh
oh we've lost your audio you can't hear
you anymore the deep state is cut you
they always seem to do that at just the
right offer two times nope getting too
close to the truth okay
yeah we still can't hear you yeah it cut
off like mid word try going out and back
in sometimes that works
strangely enough and hey ray
hi guys hey glad to be stopping in what
a what a great conversation you're
having I'll be in a board meeting but
it's a it's still the board meeting
that's really awesome I'm enjoying it
and that is I think we stopped trying to
have a board we didn't just have a it's
funny so it's one of the conversations
I'm looking to set up in two weeks is
and I just got the wording for the
technological Commons like what's
powerful about what we can create
together it's basically that's without
actually creating anything happening the
conversation what that generates but
this is kind of it like I'm like I don't
know it's everyone or is this is that
yeah I mean part of it too is we haven't
really like bore defied the board
reading yet it sort of starts off as a
board meeting and then meanders to which
yeah I think as we get more you know
sort of like actually have things to
discuss the agenda will get longer and
it'll become a more you know half an
hour board meeting topics and then half
an hour of whatever I think also once we
get it figured out um possibly doing
something like going through the
protocol of stuff right like the
incorporate like less about the
incorporation like the legal
incorporation which also to get fun used
to do that we definitely need to do at
the gaming world but even more
importantly to know what entity did know
what going through like what our values
what our was when he's gone right now
I'm hoping the tutor was talking about
values I know I have values for together
attack that especially the beginning I
was like I can't get or anyone else's
project and once it's like these things
and it has to be these things and I
still hold those four together tech in
any project I'm on has to hold those but
I think it's like just like a B's kind
of event diagram all the Venn diagrams
of what's important to me and what I
bring to the table
so is my value system right it's like
well which values are important it's
actually all the values and it's the
fact that my highest might be you know
safety and someone else's might be
justice someone else's might be equity I
don't even know it's art but like that
together text honoring is in the
diversity that those they're all the
importance and yes we called means one
two three at the highest
because we commonly hold them together
Aaron you know like kinda like the club
but one cloud right where it's like oh
look we all have integrity cuz already
doing ones that they don't make the list
because they're so common amongst us we
don't even know that other people don't
share them right and so anyway makes
sense for together tech to reverse it
and instead of saying what you have to
have just say what you can't have
because I exert going to be a lot of
right like what are the things that like
you know most people involved agree like
yeah we don't want that kind of a
project and like is it that you have to
have you know three or more of them is
if any single one of them is that yeah I
think we've had this talk a couple of
times where it's like individual
projects will have their own values and
things that they're trying to solve but
then together tech what well how have
its own it's kind of a network of
projects to say kind of if you're
joining together tech why look what do
all these people or these projects that
I'm joined together tech why did they
did you go any what do they have in
common and also I mean like I'm good a
whole different I'm gonna hold different
values my projects I'm on are gonna hold
different values and together tech like
if we're talking about in terms of that
technological Commons right so what is
it that's in that common space what
values are in that common space what
then I'm not answering that question as
Jubilee what is usually hope valuable it
is truly what benefits the Commons the
most right and it's trust transparent
like it's like that's bigger than
honestly my ethics right like it's
bigger than does it you slave labor even
because it's like right what I want is
actual truth and whether it uses slave
labor at a higher priority if not you
slave labor so that I can make mirthless
it's like it's a slightly different or
it's it's like a slightly more logical
algorithmic value system so then I can
live my values if that makes sense I
think I just okayed slave labor that's a
good if slightly uncomfortable example
is if something used in slave labor but
it uses 5% of what the competing company
uses I mean it's a massive improvement
but is it you know Nix because of that
small like
the much smaller amount is that still
negating or are we after improvement
over perfection I mean there's no right
answer right like as you said you don't
really want to come on the side of like
yeah for sure slavery like no nobody but
you know it's when do you make that call
when do you say I don't like it but it
is you know it's an improvement
yeah and it's not really especially with
slavery to be like how dare you use
slavery I'm like I'm so what are we
talking on right now we're all using
slavery and so like just say okay long
you've been only buy computers that you
zero slavery I'm not gonna be on a
computer here's your Atticus but to be
able to work back that that system to
get less and less slavery and less I was
like because of transparency which is
right we could only get cobalt fruits
like I don't know whichever silicon
through slavery whatever the thing is
that we don't get this way are there any
other places that are doing this
ethically bunam is astronomically
expensive what is our value system a
million fold times yeah maybe not I
don't know like well it's good but
owning that because it's like it's
almost like well how dare you use it
it's like we're all using it like well
zeros clearly yes the zeros the number
we want to get you and none of us are
living with zero slaves especially
nobody does joining or watching this
meeting a few people on but I completely
cuz they're silent watching this TV show
on how boats dangerous ways to get to
school and like everyone a lot of them
will have a school that has both local
or people and people who come from a
long long and they're like well these
people these kids can't learn because
they trekked forth but it's I'm like if
you don't see the ingenuity these kids
have oh who are the other ones even if
they're not getting babies become like
this and like my daughter was like like
why do they want to get to school so bad
I'm like why do I don't think it's bad
like why aren't they on an iPod at home
right why do they trekking this
like wow this seems weird that this is
what we do right now anyway good to
complete side know that somewhere in
there was reference protocol that love
and if yeah if you ever guys wanted to
try to formally informally formally you
know form a form the group a little more
cohesively yeah it would be great to
share that just you can learn about it
in the process might be the most fun
part because it does sound like you
basically have your your in formal
governance working just fine in terms of
you probably know how you're making
decisions and you're writing them down
somewhere we're on video lines if
there's a record of it it's just not
none of us agree to taking notes so we
have an agenda
so the transparent index isn't happening
yet so yeah that's totally like then it
could be the next step if and when you
guys are ready may I have a question
I spent a message on your form
from Pat protocol that love or maybe it
was your polka I'm just wondering if
maybe there's a time that we could talk
I have a project idea that maybe
collaborative or maybe I could talk
about finding a way to hire you to
design something for me I do have some
being designed already but I and I feel
like it's it's based on the Medicare in
C project so I think that chain would be
perfect for it but she kind of artist
and I feel like maybe this group isn't
right for me there was a lot of talk
last week about I don't know I just felt
really undervalued and I'm not sure I
don't feel like I fit with this because
I'm not maybe 10 or Arts Hulu or
whatever but talking about it is amazing
sure I always glad to make time for that
shadow oh sorry I your communication I'd
like to make sure we figure out where
that was and how I missed it
but if you're on Facebook that's
definitely a great way to grab me okay
I'm ma I'm really I have a lot of social
anxiety so I don't do a happy what's
that okay I can connect you to on in
messenger and add you
thank you together well I know in China
that we all like fit in in different
ways that I know from my experience
coming into the tech space and not being
very tech savvy there's a lot of times
the things feel like they're like too
technical and my brain like goes off and
sometimes I make it like I don't belong
here that from our side you're welcome
anytime your your contribution is
amazing even though you don't have a
project possibly because you don't know
a project but also you do have a project
like that and you have it yeah it's it's
it's a very important project and even
if it's not quite articulated that it's
it's um I don't know what I'm trying to
articulate but you're welcome here if
you're feeling that you don't belong
here it's not from us or if there is
something we've done or said and please
absolutely let me know because yeah I
know you I'm in the midst of reading a
book on sort of like you know building
your board and how you should structure
it and one of the key things is the
diversity on the board and like of
everything so a huge part of it is
having people who aren't super technical
so if we get too technical and you're
like I don't understand well guess what
a lot of people watching are gonna
understand either so we should maybe not
get that deep in that section and maybe
have a different one for a different
committee or something so it's a really
important part of having a really varied
board as far as like skill sets and all
right because even if you're not
technical you already seem to have a
better understanding you like
cryptocurrency did I do for sure so that
alone I'm
that's still technical so you're you
know you know more than me and at least
one area and I think you've been on
another front like with doing game B and
coming together as a team and doing any
of this stuff is like those
uncomfortable feelings that come up both
feet like internal ones like I don't
belong I'm not good enough are not but
also like the actual interconnection of
like someone says something wrong we
don't talk about it or whether it was
wrong or not it was taken the wrong it
was taken differently that it was
intended and like that that's like our
egos there's everything right and when
there gets to be uncomfortable emotions
game a the current world is about like
push them down don't feel down there now
how dare you bring this up Shiloh it's a
Gore meeting right like and that's not
because that's some of the most valuable
stuff we're gonna get is going to be
that right as an individual I'm feeling
like one that when you don't feel right
right when you're feeling like you're
not in the best mood do you show up to
these or do you not show up to these and
I think you show up if you want to right
if you're someone who value like no I
need time I don't want to be here and
you don't and if you're someone who's
like no I want it I want to show up and
be Who I am in the moment then you show
up and it's about the group allowing
that or not right maybe we do have a
rule where it's like no this is about
this thing and so you can't show up
unless you're in your highest
consciousness that's a pretty high bar
to set and so we're all gonna have
different times of being high and being
low and being and like honoring that
both in like I'm not going to contribute
the best today and I wondering that like
I'm feeling feeling and I don't know
where or why right I don't know whether
it's me I don't know whether it's I
don't know like I don't know whether
it's like what is there here but anytime
there's a uncomfortable emotion I find
that that's like there's it's there's
something there like something to learn
something to and the more willing to
share the better sorry actually why I
came today I'm really busy actually
doing a lot of yard work and I just had
to set this time aside because I was
feeling very hurt and blocked because of
it and so I just wanted to come on
they were the air or what not so okay
I'm glad you said something and then
also I mean we pretty much always stick
around after two so if there's ever a
concern that you don't want to air you
know live and recorded on YouTube that's
also an option do you want to stick
around after and say hey by the way I
didn't you know he lied saying this in
front of kind of the entire world but it
you know et cetera and then we can catch
the pup that way and can I just say that
bringing the non-technical perspective
to the table is about the best thing
that is possible here because so many
systems are designed by the tech people
who are programmers colors and and they
are so awful to use and so you know
whenever I think I see such a system
it's okay surely a developer designed
this because I can see how the thought
processes went behind the project and
why it was created this way but I can
also so I can use it its first usually
they are very ugly and secondly they
look like they were designed by someone
with like zero social skills and
consciousness about other people so
non-technical stuff is great just we
need more of this there's a really good
book on that topic called the inmates
are running the asylum that talks about
sort of the start of software and like
how it was developers that were making
choices on usability and they're like
super techie people so they made techie
usability choices other techies could
pick it up and use it it's somebody that
wasn't it's like I've known what's going
on here
and yes you but I think the copy of the
book you have is mine hey Shiloh I did
find your contact request you use the
website form cool
I got your email there perfect
I'd have to say one more thing maybe
about art is right now you guys are all
working in this in be world and also
game a and you're trying to compete in a
way either with each other or with game
a or however that is but with art you
can actually practice something before
it's a reality so you can test things
out in the real world on a diverse
public and actually get results like
real-world results without having to set
everything up and have all these rules
and laws and exacting everything is
telling everybody how it's going to be
you can actually let them guide you yeah
I love that it's very similar to what's
coming up for me this week like the art
and the dance and sorry the war in the
dance and how the war is very about
competition and there's only one winner
in the dance it's like show up and dance
and it doesn't really matter where you
are and like art is the dance and it's
funny because I always label myself as
like not an artist and I look at the
like way that I create creation in the
world and invention and it's in an
artistic format like it's it's creative
and artistic and it is it's like playing
with it and making mistakes and you're
allowed to make mistakes in art and not
getting too serious and although we're
doing serious work right we're trying to
create a world that works it's also very
important to know right that it takes
all and so if it's not fun for you if
it's not like why isn't it and how is it
on us to make it fun raise even like
working through those dynamics and that
doesn't necessarily mean working through
them here on camera whatever feels
comfortable not comfortable but my mind
went blank but but honoring them right
like not putting away and saying yes
they're welcome it's welcome for those
things to to show up and we'll deal with
as we do even if you know part of
dealing with it is on read it maybe
off-camera you know there's a lot of
money I ate all night both done landmark
I don't know federal sub Lambert there's
like behind the scenes me it means
dislike joke of like oh yeah like
landmark I'm like I should like to do a
live work it wasn't quite a bad Oh
learning from it how most of what we
react to in the world is our story about
what's happening in versus what's
actually happening and even knowing that
you don't know that like they're really
like it still a continually keep
probably not because all we reacting
right my kid does something and I'm
putting like adult emotions and add all
the intense on her and and that and that
in it and whenever you kind of like talk
about that right the emotion that's
brought up and why that emotions there
that it I don't know for me anyway a lot
of times it's like a misunderstanding on
the the reason and then I was someone
who gives out this understanding a lot
but it's it's like oh that's not how I
meant that at all and I get why people
get it that way but it's in a different
way just uh I wish as a society we had
other ways to deal with it oh where it
wasn't so considered rude to ask or rude
to clarify right to because it's like
you do just react is instead of like
wait did you mean it like this like I'm
feeling hurt because I take it like this
and then like oh no that's not I'm sorry
either easier that's what I practiced a
little bit in I mean using my son's
kindergarten we have this but of parents
and teachers are really NPC enabled so
to speak and we see being the nonviolent
communication and this is amazing and it
is so critically hard sometimes
especially to get in the mode of
actually listening to the other person
and until you start practicing that you
really don't know how hard it is and it
also discovery for me I was like and
then there was this way off in which
it's like I you said something and I go
okay what I heard what I understood is
this and this is correct me if I'm wrong
and practicing this after a while it
really allows to understand and be more
like seeing the situation from some
perspective not from the perspective of
my own head but from outside and it's
amazing how much is missed when we have
this only narrow point of view here
right so right it reminds me of a saying
seek first to understand and then to be
understood
mm-hm
Rathi near the end of the hour for the
hour-long board meeting if people want
to start racking up the thoughts we have
our Saturday morning roundtable tomorrow
at 9:00 a.m. Pacific Standard Time that
everybody is welcome to you talk about a
project or what we're looking for in a
project as well as what we are looking
forward to get out of that session that
day and come up with common solutions to
whatever problems are rising in that
space would you that every Saturday
morning and this session we switch back
and forth between an idea cafe for
projects and a board meeting for how do
we move them at a project forward how
can we create something the
technological Commons or in our first
project from the technological comments
whatever that happens to be more more in
the conversation part of that pebble so
that there at the end you guys are
talking about a lot of human
technologies human interaction all
technologies a critical visa the
protocol that love work for sure so like
the extent there's ever interest to just
take making notes and best practices in
terms of you know what the stuff comes
up how to process through they had
that's important work I'm in I'm in to
do that I didn't do some reading on the
protocol and actually the whole chain
and that seems to be like totally
interesting that I was not totally aware
of what it does before and that there is
some answer to privacy and data of the
users kept in one place and being used
by various different interfaces so there
is great possibility there and the
protocol is that's amazingly convergent
on some things I did read before like
please correct me if I'm wrong but it
seems that all the different aspects of
the protocol
our notes before passing like value
values not the best workers but
themselves but it's more like setting
banks of the river and making streams
through which the value can flow and
feedback mixes yeah yeah go one step
further is this certain extents the
banks of the river but it becomes the
banks of the river because it's actually
the sand that the water starts flowing
through and as the water find natural
path then the riverbanks start forming
to create structure around what's
emergent right now there's about 15
different collectives that are in
various processes with reflective
foundational document process two are
very active currently that that I'm
still tracking and involved with and it
just had a really terrific gathering
yesterday that's on my Facebook page a
recording of it that we're we're
launching the facilitators guild which
is other people who would love to learn
and consult and teach protocol that love
to organizations and startup phase to
actually do a collective foundational
document so we're putting together a
group of people interested in doing that
there would be more information
forthcoming about that for anyone who
might be interested or that you know is
really good kind of group facilitator
learn about it I have took it all
oh thanks for your feedback on you know
like poking holes is there any any of
the brain power that's in these game
beat groups I just love and all of it
poke the holes and tell me bro this
isn't gonna work
I might have passed Jubilees homo test I
don't know I'll have to review the
recording should see how away actually
it's perfect it was it's good it's a
good watch list called two hours of it
and yeah it was it was great thank you
think about YouTube no right see it's
more money guys than stick around